<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2020-04-19T15:31:27-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ethical Frenchie</title><subtitle>We are a family and friends based French Bulldog Breeder located in New York, NY. We welcome you to Learn more about us and our Ethically Bred French Bulldog puppies.</subtitle><author><name>James</name><email>james@ashlandharrison.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">French Bulldog Feeding: The Raw Diet</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-feeding-the-raw-diet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="French Bulldog Feeding: The Raw Diet" /><published>2020-02-12T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-12T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post23</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-feeding-the-raw-diet/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;french-bulldog-feeding-the-raw-diet&quot;&gt;French Bulldog Feeding: The Raw Diet&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;should-i-feed-my-french-bulldog-the-raw-food-diet&quot;&gt;Should I Feed My French Bulldog the Raw Food Diet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All dog owners want the absolute best for their furry companions to make sure they stick around for as long as possible and live a healthy, happy and active life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A balanced, biologically appropriate diet is the first step towards achieving that goal. Historically, dry dog kibble and canned dog food were the only choices on the market. But over the years, people became more familiar with different options like the fresh food or raw food diets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog we will dive deeper into the raw food diet, it’s benefits, risks and frequent misconceptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-the-raw-dog-food-diet&quot;&gt;What is the raw dog food diet?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raw_feeding&quot;&gt;B.A.R.F diet&lt;/a&gt; stands for two common phrases: ‘Biologically Appropriate Raw Food’ and ‘Bones and Raw Food’. Founded by veterinarian and nutritionist Dr. Ian Billinghurst, the principle is to feed dogs the diet they evolved to eat—a raw diet composed of meats and greens that are fresh, uncooked and wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The genetic makeup of domesticated dogs supports this. From Boston Terriers to St. Bernards, dogs are essentially the same as their ancestors, gray wolves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As direct descendants of wolves, dogs are simply not genetically optimized to consume the 50% carbohydrate content of today’s commercial kibbles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recommended guidelines for a BARF diet consists of 70% muscle meat, 10% raw edible bone, 7% vegetables, 5% liver, 5% other secreting organ, 2% seeds or nuts, and 1% fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-the-benefits-of-raw-feeding&quot;&gt;What are the benefits of raw feeding?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Firmer stools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Improved digestion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Healthier skin and coat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Reduced allergy symptoms&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Leaner, more muscular build;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 60% of dogs are overweight or obese based on body condition scoring, which leads to a number of related conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been many reports of improved health when chronically ill pets were switched from a commercial product to a raw dog food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-downsides-of-raw-feeding&quot;&gt;The downsides of raw feeding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally think the benefits outweigh the downsides, but it comes down to every individual and their budget as well as their household situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	First downside would be the inconvenience of feeding raw vs. feeding kibble. Raw food has a shorter shelf life and needs to be refrigerated/freezed at all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Second is the possibility of contamination – for humans. The dogs have a short and acidic digestive system, so they aren’t susceptible to Salmonella or E-coli infections. Always wash your food after handling raw food. Wash the dog bowl with soap and warm water right after feeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/raw_feeding_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of French Bulldog Raw Food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;frequent-misconceptions-about-raw-feeding&quot;&gt;Frequent Misconceptions About Raw Feeding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Raw meat is contaminated/infested with parasites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick meat that is labeled as “human grade”, that meat is inspected and clear of parasites. I would however steer away from wild meat (bear, beaver, wild pig, etc.). Bacteria is found everywhere, even on kibble, but dogs have a short digestive track and usually aren’t affected by Salmonella or E-coli, like I mentioned before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**2. My veterinary advised against raw feeding and suggested the science diet instead. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to understand that “veterinarian” doesn’t equal “nutritionist”. Most vets have very little nutritional training, and what they get in school is funded by the pet food companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vets that don’t understand the dietary needs of dogs (and cats) will recommend kibble or canned food, so that each meal is complete and balanced. They will tell you that your dog will get salmonella or e-coli from raw meat, etc..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dogs eat poop, road kill and lick their behinds every day. . Their system is different from ours. If we ate the stuff they did, we would for sure get very sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_ Dogs have a short digestive system made to handle raw meat and bones(raw bones, NEVER COOKED BONES), the bacteria that is present isn’t a problem for a healthy dog. _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Is kibble bad for my dog? My dog has been eating it for years and had no issues.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do I start with this one.. First dogs don’t have a nutritional need for ingredients like wheat, corn, etc and the grains and fillers in the commercial dog food are often the root of allergies and digestion issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most commercial dog foods also have artificial color, sugar, artificial flavoring, too much salt, etc.. The goal of adding all these things is to make them flavorful and appealing to your dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kibble is cooked on extremely high temperatures which destroys most of the nutrients that are beneficial to your dog&lt;/strong&gt; (enzymes, vitamins, beneficial bacteria, fatty acids). The processing kibble goes through makes all the dogs internal organs work harder to extract the nutrients that have survived the extruding process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kibble industry of course improved a lot. There are many “grain free” and “organic” kibble options, but at the end of the day you are still feeding your dog a highly processed, nutritionally low meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Dogs just like human can SURVIVE on a low quality diet(read fast food), but they can’t THRIVE on it. Feed your dog a species appropriate nutrition and watch him live a long, healthy, issue free life.**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-raw-feed-your-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;How To Raw Feed Your French Bulldog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-frozen-and-dehydrated-raw-food-brands&quot;&gt;1. Frozen and Dehydrated Raw Food Brands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pet Smart and Pet Co carry most of these option. The difference between frozen and freeze dried/dehydrated is the storing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to keep the dehydrated raw food in the fridge and it’s completely safe so carry it around. It’s best to re-hydrate is before serving by using bone broth, warm water, goat milk..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Finstinct-by-natures-variety-frozen%2Fdp%2F170898&quot;&gt;Instinct Frozen Raw Pet Food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fprimal-chicken-formula-nuggets-grain%2Fdp%2F43376&quot;&gt;Primal Dehydrated Raw Food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fstella-chewys-duck-duck-goose-dinner%2Fdp%2F121086&quot;&gt;Stella&amp;amp;Chewy’s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fnulo-freestyle-grain-free-duck-recipe%2Fdp%2F162466&quot;&gt;Nulo Freeze Dried Raw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fhonest-kitchen-grain-free-chicken%2Fdp%2F34268&quot;&gt;The Honest Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fspot-farms-grain-free-duck-dehydrated%2Fdp%2F177172&quot;&gt;Spot Farms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fvisionary-pet-foods-raw-frozen-keto%2Fdp%2F177390&quot;&gt;Visionary Keto Pet Foods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/raw_feeding_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Frozen Foods&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-raw-food-subscriptions&quot;&gt;2. Raw Food Subscriptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t to fond of preparing your own meal, or confused about creating a balanced meal you can always rely on experts to do it for you. Below are some raw food subscription services that will bring the food to your door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wefeedraw.com/&quot;&gt;We Feed Raw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://primalpooch.com/&quot;&gt;Primal Pooch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rawwild.com/&quot;&gt;Raw Wild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mypetcarnivore.com/&quot;&gt;My Pet Carnivore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rawpawspetfood.com/&quot;&gt;Raw Paws Pet Food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-preparing-your-own-raw-food&quot;&gt;3. Preparing Your Own Raw Food&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true, raw food subscriptions and food brands tend to be more expensive, but you can choose the cheaper route and prepare the meals yourself. You definitely need to be careful and do a lot of research to make sure you are balancing the nutrients correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What should the basic raw meal structure look like:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	1 ½ cups of raw meat, partially on the bone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	½ veggies and fruit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Multivitamin/mineral product&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Omega 3 in a form of fish oil or general omega 3 supplement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**How much should you feed? **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An adult dog needs to eat just over 2% of his bodyweight in food each day (whether it’s raw dog food, or homemade food that you’re cooking for him).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for a 10lb dog that’s just under 1/4lb of food; for a 50lb dog just over 1lb, and for a 100lb dog about 2.5lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use this guide to figure out how much your dog needs, but of course bear in mind that all dogs are different and that these figures are guidelines only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Ratio can be 75% - 95% meat/bones/organs and 5% -25% vegetables&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	The bones in any raw dog food recipe should have an equal amount of meat and bone (ie a 1:1 ratio). Big bones with just a little bit of meat aren’t nearly as good as smaller bones with more meat on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Overall bone to meat ratio can be approx 1:3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/raw_feeding_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Types of Raw Meat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-kind-of-meat-you-should-use&quot;&gt;What kind of meat you should use:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Chicken - chicken necks, thighs, wings and even feet are great choices&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Turkey - as above&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Duck - as above&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Lamb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Beef&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Rabbit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Venison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Wild game birds such as Pheasant or Partridge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Organ Meat such as liver, kidneys and so on are excellent, but rich, so use sparingly at first&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Whole fish of just about any kind are fine, but raw salmon often isn’t recommended&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;safe-to-use-vegetables&quot;&gt;Safe to use vegetables:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Brussel Sprouts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Carrots&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Cauliflower&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Okra&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Green Beans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Peas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Pumpkin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Squash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Romaine Lettuce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Parsley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Celery&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Sweet Potatoes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;safe-to-use-fruits&quot;&gt;Safe to use fruits:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Apples (pitts are poisonous, make sure to remove them)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Bananas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Pears&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Strawberries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Blueberries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;extra-ingredients-you-could-add&quot;&gt;Extra ingredients you could add:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other ingredients that can be used to add variety and extra nutritional value to raw dog food recipes.
 They do not need to be added daily, and once or twice a week for most is generally enough…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Kefir as a probiotic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Raw Eggs - including the shells which need to be ground to a fine powder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Almonds (NOT Macadamia Nuts)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Sunflower seeds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Wheatgrass&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Kelp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this blog convinced you or at least opened your mind to  benefits of raw feeding. Like I mentioned before, I do understand that kibble is way more convenient, but the BARF diet is a diet closest to your dogs origin and  proven to help maintain longevity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>renee</name></author><category term="French Bulldog Feeding" /><category term="picks" /><summary type="html">French Bulldog Feeding: The Raw Diet</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/raw_feeding.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/raw_feeding.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">French Bulldogs and New York Lottery | Here to Make Your Day with Frenchies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-television-commercial-new-york-lottery-animal-actors-inc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="French Bulldogs and New York Lottery | Here to Make Your Day with Frenchies" /><published>2020-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post27</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-television-commercial-new-york-lottery-animal-actors-inc/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;french-bulldogs-on-tv&quot;&gt;French Bulldogs on TV&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look Ma! We’re on TV!  2019 Was a great year for Ethical Frenchie, one of many lessons and many new friends. So it was only fitting that we would receive a random call from Animal Actors Inc telling us that “we’re up next”. The read carpet was roleld out and our babies were ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;uk-section uk-section-large&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;uk-container uk-container-xsmall uk-position-relative uk-text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section-title-center uk-margin-large-bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-title uk-margin-remove uk-text-center&quot;&gt;Behind The Scenes!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;div&gt;
    
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;uk-article-content&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/390228658&quot; width=&quot;360&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we didn’t exactly have the diversity of puppies needed we jumped on the phone and called our customers whom had recently adopted puppies from us to ask “Would you like to see your puppy on TV!?”  Every single family responded relucantly :-( which shows exactly how passionate our furever homes are when we place puppies.   Alas, we found a couple extra to stand in with the puppies of ours and it was lights camera action!   Below are some of the clips of what its like on a real tv commercial shoot (And of course, They were the most popular attraction on the whole film studio lot)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t Forget to Follow Us on Instagram Below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/IGCTA2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And again thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;Animal Actors Inc&quot;&gt;http://www.animalactorsinc.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¹ Animal Actors Inc, Ethical Frenchie LLC, New York Lotto&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>james</name></author><category term="French Bulldog puppy" /><category term="news" /><category term="picks" /><summary type="html">French Bulldogs on TV</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/nylotto.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/nylotto.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ethical Frenchie’s Guide To Dog Health</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/ethical-frenchie-guide-to-dog-health/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ethical Frenchie’s Guide To Dog Health" /><published>2020-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/post23</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/ethical-frenchie-guide-to-dog-health/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/sick-french-bulldog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a sick french bulldog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-guide-to-raising-a-healthy-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;Our Guide To Raising a Healthy French Bulldog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s well known that &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/blog/ethical-frenchie-guide-to-dog-health/&quot; title=&quot;French Bulldogs Health&quot;&gt;French Bulldogs &lt;/a&gt; fall under one of those “sensitive” and “issue prone” breeds. And there is no denying that purebred dogs tend to be susceptible to sickness more than mutts, which is due to the smaller genetic diversity pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing to keep in mind is things aren’t always black and white. 
Just like with humans, it’s possible to avoid genetic issues and susceptibilities with your dogs as well, and food plays a big role. So let’s start with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;food&quot;&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gut represents 80% of your dog’s immune system. It’s important to keep the gut flora balanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can do that by feeding your Frenchie companion a diet they were designed to eat. The best way to go at it is by preparing your own meals (fresh or raw), or investing in a good fresh food subscription service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Dogs are designed to eat a moist diet that consists of meat as its first ingredients, as well as some fresh vegetables. **
Kibble is problematic, due to it’s high starch content. Starch is well known to cause inflammation and definitely does not support a healthy microbiome for dogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Live bacteria from fresh food on the other hand promotes just that. It’s vital to include it into your dog’s everyday meal. If you are still loyal to kibble – boost it with fresh ingredients daily.
Also, adding a quality probiotic never hurts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fhonest-kitchen-daily-boosters-instant%2Fdp%2F177081&quot;&gt;You can get one here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;turmeric-golden-paste-food-booster&quot;&gt;Turmeric Golden Paste Food Booster&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/tumeric.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of Tumeric as a supplement for Frenchies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Have you every heard of the incredible healing effects of curcumin? **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curcumin is the main compound of turmeric and can fight allergies, relieve pain, boost the immune system and prevent cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many turmeric dog supplements available online, but there ain’t nothing like the home-made thing, am I right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This turmeric golden paste is super easy to make and will last your for about 2 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;INGREDIENTS:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup organic turmeric powder (Organic turmeric powder contains more curcumin)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 to 1 ½ cups filtered water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ teaspoons freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup organic cold pressed or coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;DIRECTIONS:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  Mix the turmeric with the water in a pan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  Start with 1 cup water and add more only if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  Stir the liquid on medium/low heat and in about 7 to 10 minutes, it should form a thick paste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  If your paste looks watery, just add a bit more turmeric and heat it for another couple of minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  Once you’ve got a paste, add the pepper and oil, then stir it very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  Allow the mixture to cool, then place it in a jar with a lid and store it in your fridge. Ideally, you should store the paste for no more than two weeks … after that, you’ll want to make a fresh batch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Start by adding ¼ to your Frenchie’s meal. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;if-allergies-arise-try-fighting-them-naturally-first&quot;&gt;If Allergies Arise Try Fighting Them Naturally First&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Veterinary prescribed medication is very effective, but it should be considered the last resort. It removes the reaction to the allergen by suppressing the immune system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is once the immune system is suppressed the body becomes a target for many different illnesses, including cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your French Bulldog is suffering from uncontrollable allergies and none of the natural remedies are doing the trick, the next step would be doing a simple allergy test to determinate the trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The allergen can be anything from food, pollen, certain types of grass and even human dandruff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogsnaturallymagazine.com/why-i-dont-vaccinate-my-dogs-at-all/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Full article here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-challenge-the-immune-system-with-any-vaccines-unless-100-necessary&quot;&gt;Don’t Challenge The Immune System With Any Vaccines, Unless 100% Necessary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/vaccine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of canine vaccine as a supplement for Frenchies&quot; title=&quot;Vaccine for French Bulldogs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vaccines are a wonderful thing. In fact 80% of little puppies would never make it through their first few months of life without them. Their immune system is week and undeveloped, so diseases like Parvo, Distemper, etc can be deadly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However… over vaccinating became a huge problem in the last decade. The vaccines your tiny Frenchie pup gets give him protection to up to 7 years, so why are we vaccinating our pets and giving them boosters yearly? Rabies vaccine is required by law and 100% necessary. **The other ones? Not so much. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently read an article that spoke to me, so I had to share. And I quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;” Our dogs are in the midst of an epidemic. It’s not an epidemic of viral disease, but of chronic ill health. They’re besieged with itchy, pus-laden, scabby skin; vomit and diarrhea are the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One in every hundred dogs suffers from epilepsy, and an even higher number of  dogs live with painful arthritis.  Allergies are also reaching epidemic proportions: dogs are becoming allergic to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Dr Jean W Dodds, an eminent vet and researcher, both allergic and autoimmune diseases have been rising since the introduction of modified live virus vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autoimmune diseases are where the body attacks self; they include cancer, leukemia, thyroid disease, Addisons, Grave’s disease, autoimmune hemolytic anemia, rheumatoid arthritis, diabetes, lupus, thrombocytopenia, organ failure, skin inflammations, and more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/creativeref:1011l31349&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://creative.prf.hn/source/camref:1100l86im/creativeref:1011l31349&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;brush-those-teeth&quot;&gt;Brush Those Teeth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago we posted a blog called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/blog/increase-french-bulldog-lifespan&quot;&gt;Increasing French Bulldog Lifespan&lt;/a&gt;”, and pointed out how important oral care actually is. You should brush your Frenchie’s teeth as often as possible, and 1x per week at a minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your Frenchie isn’t fond of the teeth brushing ritual, make sure you ad least invest in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Ftropiclean-fresh-breath-drops-22oz%2Fdp%2F114717&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fresh Breath water additive like this one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie, life gets hectic and even I don’t brush my dogs teeth everyday, I do however use the water additive constantly as it promotes oral health and fights bad puppy breath as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-your-frenchie-slim&quot;&gt;Keep Your Frenchie Slim&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/slim-frenchie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of quite chubby frenchies&quot; title=&quot;Rather chubby French Bulldogs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French Bulldogs are naturally wide and stocky, but wide and stocky doesn’t equal chunky. You might think it looks cute and adorable seeing a Frenchie with a few extra rolls, but it’s far from that. It’s dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People don’t realize that 70% of family pets are overweight. A healthy French Bulldog should be slim, muscular, and the rib cage should be easily visible with every inhale. 
Even though they are known as the perfect apartment dog, cuddle buddy and couch potato, they still require a certain level of exercise to maintain a healthy figure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting your French Bulldog get overweight will bring a series of problems, including arthritis, hearth, breathing and eye problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Think of it as a domino effect, and I’ll give an example. 
**Let’s say your Frenchie is overweight and the excess weight is overwhelming the joints leading to arthritis. Arthritis causes major discomfort and the state of pain is known to weaken the immune system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weak immune system makes the host more susceptible to other life-threatening conditions, including cancer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feed a quality diet, without overfeeding, and remember less is more. Don’t feed table scraps – a small piece of cheese ingested by your dog equals a chocolate bar ingested by a human. If you want to provide a heathy in between the meal snack for your Frenchie – try carrots or blueberries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;supplements-you-should-consider-using&quot;&gt;Supplements You Should Consider Using&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Falaska-naturals-wild-alaskan-salmon%2Fdp%2F105390&quot;&gt;• Omega 3 Supplement or regular Fish Oil&lt;/a&gt; {:target=”_blank”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fhonest-kitchen-daily-boosters-instant%2Fdp%2F177081&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;• Quality Probiotic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/pubref:renee/adref:ethicalfrenchie/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fhealers-turmeric-golden-paste-mix-dog%2Fdp%2F203177&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Turmeric Supplement or the DIY Turmeric Golden Paste&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fzesty-paws-mobility-bites-hip-joint%2Fdp%2F226707&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Glucosamine Joint Supplement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fonly-natural-pet-free-range-chicken%2Fdp%2F179023&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bone Broth to rehydrate dry kibble food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/creativeref:1100l29658&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://creative.prf.hn/source/camref:1100l86im/creativeref:1100l29658&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; width=&quot;222&quot; height=&quot;143&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re on the market for a new family member, &lt;a href=&quot;/puppies&quot;&gt;check out our puppies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>renee</name></author><category term="French Bulldog Health Issues" /><category term="news" /><category term="picks" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/fawn-sick-french-bulldog.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/fawn-sick-french-bulldog.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">French Bulldog Grooming and Care 101</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-grooming-and-care-101" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="French Bulldog Grooming and Care 101" /><published>2020-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-grooming-and-care-101">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-the-french-bulldog-care-101-consists-of&quot;&gt;What Does The French Bulldog Care 101 Consists of?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you start looking for French Bulldog Puppies for sale it’s important to research the breed and learn about the Frenchie care regime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French Bulldog care is not a piece of cake. You will have to be thorough and consistent with caring for your furry friend. Your utmost focus will have to be on food and grooming. So let’s start with that…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feeding&quot;&gt;Feeding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose a high-quality food, but don’t be scared to spice it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What do we mean by that?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t rely on one food brand alone. Mix and match. Find what works best for your puppy and keep things fresh. I probably mentioned this in each blog I write, but I highly encourage feeding your furry friend fresh or raw based diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will avoid allergies, yeast and digestion issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fresh food is also one of the mains steps you can take to increase your French Bulldogs Lifespan (link to the blog “increase French bulldog lifespan).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid table scraps and unhealthy snacks. Remember if it’s unhealthy for you, it’s probably not good for your dog either. Overweight French Bulldogs are also more prone to joint, eye and breathing issues. Keeping your dog lean is one of the most important steps to good French Bulldog care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/french-bulldog-feeding-the-raw-diet/&quot;&gt;Click here to learn more about the diet we recommend for French Bulldogs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grooming&quot;&gt;Grooming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1ears&quot;&gt;1.Ears&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bulldogs tend to develop ear infections if you don’t pay special attention to those bat ears. Clean them weekly or as soon as you notice wax buildup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use a simple ear cleaning solution like &lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fvirbac-epi-otic-advanced-ear-cleaner%2Fdp%2F52807&quot;&gt;Epi-Optic Ear Cleaning solution&lt;/a&gt; or ear cleaning wipes. Both are as effective, but I personally prefer liquid over wipes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to hear a little tip that will help to avoid yeasty ears?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you notice that your French Bulldog is more prone to yeast ear infections take matters into your own hands by adding a few drops of apple cider vinegar to your pups’ water, daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-thaaat-face&quot;&gt;2. Thaaat Face&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep that adorable face clean and yeast free. Face folds should be groomed daily and kept dry to avoid bacterial infections. After cleaning – apply the &lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fsquishface-wrinkle-paste-dog-skin%2Fdp%2F189798&quot;&gt;Squishface Bulldog Balm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another Natural Dog Company product that should be your go it is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.naturaldogcompany.com/collections/all/products/snout-soother-tin&quot;&gt;snout soother&lt;/a&gt;. Apply it on your French Bulldogs nose daily to prevent it from crusting up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-teeth&quot;&gt;3.	Teeth&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, my friends. Teeth cleaning is a must. It’s not only going to save you a couple of 100$ when it comes to professional teeth cleaning but will also prolong your Frenchies life expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not that difficult and doing it 1x per week is enough. If your Frenchie refuses to cooperate you can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Ftropiclean-fresh-breath-drops-22oz%2Fdp%2F114717&quot;&gt;Fresh Breath water additive&lt;/a&gt; that fights plaque, prevents gingivitis and eliminates bad breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-bath-time&quot;&gt;4. Bath Time&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t over-do it. And use a good hypoallergenic shampoo followed up by a quality conditioner for a silky and soft coat. We highly recommend this Hydrating Butter leave-in conditioner by Warren London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over bathing will lead to dry skin that might cause irritation and itching. That’s not always the case, but chances are, it’s going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what shampoo should you use for your Frenchie’s sensitive coat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2F4-legger-organic-hypo-allergenic%2Fdp%2F141858&quot;&gt;•	4-Legger Organic, Hypo-Allergenic, Lemongrass &amp;amp; Aloe Dog Shampoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fmiconahextriz-shampoo-dogs-cats-16-oz%2Fdp%2F114184&quot;&gt;•	MiconaHex+Triz Shampoo for Dogs &amp;amp; Cats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Frocco-roxie-supply-co-calm-dog%2Fdp%2F171950&quot;&gt;•	Rocco &amp;amp; Roxie Supply Co. Calm Dog Shampoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;5paws--nails&quot;&gt;5.Paws &amp;amp; Nails&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check your dog’s pads regularly. Not just for cleanliness but to ensure that they are not dry, cracked, or injured in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excessive hair may grow between your dog’s toes. It can become matted or cause other problems. It should be trimmed to be even with the paw pads or slightly shorter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This must be done carefully to prevent cutting your dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep your dog’s nails trimmed. Your vet and/or groomer can show you how to safely trim nails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not feel comfortable doing it on your own, it is usually a quick and inexpensive trip to a groomer or your veterinarian’s office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important not to cut too close to the quick since it can cause bleeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-your-french-bulldog-in-shape&quot;&gt;Keep Your French Bulldog in Shape&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French Bulldogs don’t need excessive exercise and tire quickly, but that doesn’t mean you don’t have to keep your pup in shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting overweight will have a detrimental effect on their joins as well as their breathing. Kidney disease, heart disease, diabetes, and many others are also conditions linked to overweight French Bulldogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your French Bulldog should be the leanest possible – without the ribs being visible. Ribs should be easily felt, but only visible once the dog inhales.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be scared to do light exercise with your Frenchie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do we mean by light exercise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything from visiting the dog park, playing fetch and tug of war to walking with a lightweight vest to build strength and muscle mass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build up their fitness slowly over a couple of weeks/months, but of course, make sure you don’t over-exercise them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><category term="French Bulldog Grooming" /><category term="French Bulldog Care" /><category term="French Bulldog Health" /><summary type="html">What Does The French Bulldog Care 101 Consists of?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/frenchie-grooming-tips_hero.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/frenchie-grooming-tips_hero.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">French Bulldog Colors Explained</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/french-bulldog-colors-explained/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="French Bulldog Colors Explained" /><published>2020-01-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/post12</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/french-bulldog-colors-explained/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;french-bulldog-colors-the-standard-and-the-rare&quot;&gt;French Bulldog Colors. The Standard and The Rare.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get so many questions about French Bulldog colors on a daily basis. I’ve scrolled online trying to find an article that covers all the French Bulldog Colors and show it to my customers as an example, but nothing extensive popped up, so I decided it’s time to write my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try to keep it as simple as possible as well as cover some basic questions regarding pricing. Keep in mind that the prices vary based on color, bloodlines and breeding rights. It will cost you more to get a specific dog with a full AKC registration, than getting it just as a family pet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;standard-french-bulldog-colors-and-patterns&quot;&gt;Standard French Bulldog Colors and Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which are standard French Bulldog colors and patterns? Let’s start at the beginning..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1897, the only original breed standard was considered brindle. After the 1911 standard revision they approved additional standard colors and patterns like fawn, cream, piebald,.. To this day any deviation from the standard equals disqualification. The standard &lt;strong&gt;French Bulldog colors&lt;/strong&gt; are the only ones allowed to compete in the ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acceptable colors – All brindle, fawn, white, brindle and white, and any color except&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;those which constitute disqualification. All colors are acceptable with the exception of solid black, mouse, liver, black and tan, black and white, and white with black, which are disqualifications. Black means black without a trace of brindle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AKC, American Kennel club&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are trying to invest into a standard colored French Bulldog, from a responsible breeder – as a pet only, you will usually be looking at prices between 2,500-3,000$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However a standard color price can still go up to 5,000 – 6,000$ if bought from a breeder with champion bloodlines and amazing quality French Bulldogs.
{ include igcta3.html}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;brindle-french-bulldog-pattern&quot;&gt;Brindle French Bulldog Pattern&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/brindle-french-bulldog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a brindle french bulldog puppy laying on the floor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brindle  is one of the most common French Bulldog patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brindle French Bulldog&lt;/strong&gt; has a base coat of fawn hairs through which black hairs extend in bands to produce a coat that can range from a tiger brindle in which fawn hairs predominate to the more common dark brindles in which the black hairs predominate. The light version with fawn hairs that predominate is also known as a “reverse brindle”, and it’s generally more rare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;piebald-pattern&quot;&gt;Piebald Pattern&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/piebald.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a pied french bulldog standing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;piebald&lt;/strong&gt; is not a French Bulldog color, it’s a pattern. &lt;strong&gt;Pied&lt;/strong&gt; animal is one that has a &lt;strong&gt;pattern&lt;/strong&gt; of pigmented spots on an unpigmented (white) background of hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;pied French Bulldog&lt;/strong&gt; comes in multiple standard color variations. Brindle pied, fawn pied, red fawn pied, etc.. Of course pied can also come in an exotic color variation, but we will discuss that more in depth further down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cream-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;Cream French Bulldog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/cream-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a true cream French Bulldog Puppy standing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a &lt;strong&gt;cream French Bulldog&lt;/strong&gt;? Many light &lt;strong&gt;fawn French Bulldogs&lt;/strong&gt; are mistaken for a cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A true cream Frenchie will look slightly off white throughout – solid color. Its a recessive dilute from the fawn coat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have no markings on them, they have black pigment, black noses, black eye rims, black paw pads, and black lips. The DNA of a true cream French Bulldog is different than the one of the light fawn.
{ include igcta4.html}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://frenchbulldogsaustralia.com.au/french-bulldog-puppy-buyers-guide/true-cream-vs-fawn-vs-pied/&quot; title=&quot;Cream French Bulldog color&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to read more about the differences between these French Bulldog Colors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fawn-french-bulldog-colors&quot;&gt;Fawn French Bulldog Colors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/fawn-french-bulldog-colors.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a beautiful fawn french bulldog male&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;fawn French Bulldog&lt;/strong&gt; colors come in different shades, from very light, almost cream looking ones, to a deep red fawn. They can have a mask, like the one pictured above, or be maskless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fawn can also be combined with an exotic color in which the dilution affects the “black mask”, eyes, nose and paw pads (Blue fawn, lilac fawn, chocolate fawn,..)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exotic-french-bulldog-colors-and-patterns&quot;&gt;Exotic French Bulldog Colors and Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exotic Colors and Patterns in the French Bulldog breed&lt;/strong&gt; are the one that aren’t approved by the AKC and can’t participate in the ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can still be AKC registered and are 100% French Bulldogs, but unfortunately can’t compete due to their coat color being an instant disqualification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blue-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;Blue French Bulldog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/blue-frenchie-puppy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a blue french bulldog puppy with a red collar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beautiful &lt;strong&gt;blue (gray) French Bulldog color&lt;/strong&gt; is a results of a dilution gene. The dilution gene affects &lt;strong&gt;eumelanin&lt;/strong&gt; (liver and black coats), in some instances, the red coat as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a dog has two copies of the d allele (dd), a black dog will become blue. The coat range is wide – from very light gray to almost black, but even in that case it can be visible that the dog is dd, by looking at the color shade of his nose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;blue French Bulldog&lt;/strong&gt; color is in the rare or exotic color price range. It will cost you between 4000-6000 $ to get a blue canine companion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/blue-pied-french-bulldog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blue pied french bulldog puppy with blue eyes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the coat colors can come in a variation with a pattern (piebald, brindle, merle) + a different color. The puppy picture above is a Blue Pied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/puppies/&quot; title=&quot;Blue French Bulldog Puppies&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to check out our Blue French Bulldog Puppies available&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lilac-french-bulldog-colors&quot;&gt;Lilac French Bulldog Colors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/lilac.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lilac French Bulldog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These rare lilacs are a result of their parents blue and chocolate DNA. The same dilution gene that causes a black dog to become blue (like mentioned above), causes a chocolate/liver dog to become a lilac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.doggenetics.co.uk/dilutes.html#isabella&quot; title=&quot;Isabella dilution&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to learn more about this type of dilution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lilac French Bulldog dog will have the genotype &lt;strong&gt;bbdd&lt;/strong&gt; (homozygous for liver, homozygous for dilution). Lilac dogs are usually very light blue, almost silver looking, with light eyes and pinkish tint on their muzzle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to their unique appearance they run in the higher price range of 5000-7000$.
{ include igcta.html}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chocolate-liver&quot;&gt;Chocolate/ Liver&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/chocolate-frenchie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a Chocolate colored French Bulldog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the chocolate color case, the dilution of the black color happen on the B locus. It is recessive, so &lt;strong&gt;b&lt;/strong&gt; is liver and &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; is non-liver, and in order for a dog to be liver it must have the genotype &lt;strong&gt;bb&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;merle-pattern&quot;&gt;Merle Pattern&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/merle-pattern.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a tiny merle french bulldog puppy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The merle gene creates mottled patches of color in a solid or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Piebald&quot; title=&quot;Piebald&quot;&gt;piebald&lt;/a&gt; coat, and it can affect skin &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pigment&quot; title=&quot;Pigment&quot;&gt;pigment&lt;/a&gt; as well. This pattern is very controversial in the French Bulldog community since it can cause severe health issues, if two merles are bred together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A merle should only be bred to a dog with a solid coat color. The merle gene itself, does not cause any health issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merle dogs will usually have bright blue eyes, or odd looking eyes (heterochromia iridum). &lt;strong&gt;Heterochromia Iridum&lt;/strong&gt; is a difference in coloration of the iris. Merle French Bulldog colors are rare and of course in the higher price range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;platinum-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;Platinum French Bulldog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/platinum-frenchie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a platinum colored French Bulldog male&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An exotic color covered in cream, is what it’s called a &lt;strong&gt;Platinum&lt;/strong&gt;. Their coat color is cream, but you can see signs of dilution by looking at their nose, eyes, lips and paw pads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a regular cream French Bulldog would have a black nose, dark eyes and black paw pads, the Platinum French Bulldog will have a diluted version of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coat-color-combined-with-tan-points&quot;&gt;Coat Color Combined with Tan Points&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another very beautiful and unique coloration. The price range is wide. You can expect to pay 3000$ for a Black and Tan French Bulldog, to up to 6000-7000$ for a Lilac and Tan or Merle and Tan one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;black-and-tan-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;Black and Tan French Bulldog&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/black-and-tan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a black and tan french bulldog male&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;blue-and-tan-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;Blue and Tan French Bulldog&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/blue-and-tan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blue and tan french bulldog puppy on the grass&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lilac-and-tan-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;Lilac and Tan French Bulldog&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/lilac-and-tan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of a beautiful lilac and tan french bulldog male&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;merle-and-tan-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;Merle and Tan French Bulldog&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/merle-and-tan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a tiny merle and tan french bulldog puppy &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;black-and-black-pied-french-bulldog-colors&quot;&gt;Black and Black Pied French Bulldog Colors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/black-french-bulldog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of a black french bulldog laying on the bed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A non-standard color in the standard color price range. These beauties deviate from the acceptable coat colors, but are definitely still in the lower price range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A French Bulldog is considered black if the coat color is solid without any signs of brindle, which is rare. Even if a puppy appears black, that might not be the case. A truly &lt;strong&gt;black French Bulldog&lt;/strong&gt; has an unique DNA of a/a.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will cost you around 2500$ to bring a black or a black pied French Bulldog home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/black-and-white.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of a pied french bulldog going for a walk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>james</name></author><category term="french bulldog theft, frenchie theft, featured, pick" /><summary type="html">French Bulldog Colors. The Standard and The Rare.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/french-bulldog-colors.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/french-bulldog-colors.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Here are the 4 types of French Bulldog Breeders near you in 2020 | by Ethical Frenchie</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-ethics-of-where-to-find-a-french-bulldog-puppy-for-your-family/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Here are the 4 types of French Bulldog Breeders near you in 2020 | by Ethical Frenchie" /><published>2019-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post26</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-ethics-of-where-to-find-a-french-bulldog-puppy-for-your-family/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;here-are-the-4-types-of-french-bulldog-breeders-near-you-in-2020&quot;&gt;Here are the 4 types of French Bulldog Breeders near you in 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one believed everything printed in the media, one would know that French Bull Dogs, more commonly referred to as Frenchies, are either among the most popular breeds in the world, or they are the breed quickly losing its former popularity. Among Frenchie owners – correction, among Frenchies with human caretakers, there is no wane in popularity. I came to this conclusion after polling the two who permit me to share their fully-furnished home with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of popularity status, Frenchie puppies still demand ridiculously high prices. Perhaps you have perused online forums looking for one of those adorable squishy-faced pups with attitude and decided that $4000 or more is ridiculous for a pet. I cannot argue with that conclusion. So, why are Frenchies so pricey? One obvious answer is capitalism 101: supply and demand. Frenchies are notoriously difficult to breed. More often than not, a helping hand is needed, followed by artificial insemination. The unique bone structure of these wonderful dogs makes “hooking up” nearly impossible for some. Though not from a lack of trying on the part of the male or female. Both will physically exhaust themselves, partially due to their brachycephalic modified breathing passages. The human factor adds to the cost for both the male and the female. Because the process requires assistance, the natural opportunities to fertilize multiple batches of eggs gets reduced, which leads to fewer puppies per litter. Litters of two to four puppies are quite common. Limited litter size drives the supply and demand part of the high costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another factor arises out of the pedigree of each litter if you seek a puppy from a line of champion show dogs. If that is your thing, bring your wallet; or your Amex Black card. If you are considering showing your puppy, be prepared to shell out more cash for DNA testing to add credence to the kennel club pedigree, and to rule out most of the known inherited diseases and other congenital propensities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not interested in spending thousands of dollars to participate in the show circuit and are seeking to add a perpetual two-year-old to your family, you have options. Here I diverge from the people who claim that only professionals should breed dogs. Yes, there is an argument that shelters and rescues should get your business ahead of any type of breeder. I agree, at least in part, with this mindset. Shelter or rescue dogs require a home, and you obviously have room for one. However, when was the last time you saw a Frenchie in your local shelter? To be clear, Frenchies end up in shelters, but it is an infrequent occurrence. Unless you are at the shelter looking at new arrivals daily, the chances that you get dibs on a Frenchie are slim to none. Do look, though; maybe you are one of the people with outstanding luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here, the places to find the Frenchie of your dreams become somewhat controversial – if you care what breed-purists and shelter-only activists think. While I support, with donations and advocating for the local shelters, I do not always agree with the opinions of my friends in the animal rescue business. When someone puts in the effort to learn about the health needs, possible genetic risks, diet needs, space needs, exercise requirements, and the many other factors for a particular breed, they might just want that breed of dog. How others supplant an individual’s desire with their opinions is something I will never understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Including show breeders, there are other sources with varying ethical concerns for prospective owners of Frenchie puppies. Listed here in order from least ethical to most ethical, in my opinion: puppy mills, backyard breeders, pet stores, show breeders, and family breeders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/igcta4.png&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;french-bulldog-puppy-mills&quot;&gt;French Bulldog Puppy Mills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just what the name implies; a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.humanesociety.org/2019/05/annual-horrible-hundred-report-identifies-problem-puppy-mills-in-u-s-reveals-usda-is-failing-to-crack-down-on-violators.html&quot; title=&quot;French Bulldog Puppy Mills&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;French Bulldog Puppy Mills&lt;/a&gt; is a setup that allows for the commercial breeding of dogs while housing the dogs outside of the home. Many puppy mills use prefabricated buildings with stacks of kennels along the walls, and those dogs spend most of their lives living in those confined kennels. The dogs get outside for a minimum amount to exercise and hopefully avoid soiling their cages. You will usually find multiple breeds of dogs in a puppy mill. You also see more of the breeds whose puppies bring hefty prices. You will also find some midrange priced breeds in many of these operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A puppy mill has puppies available almost all year. To help prevent group-cycling, operators move the females between buildings to ensure that they have females who come into season throughout the year. Doing so likely contributes to the health of the male dogs that they use for studs. Here is an anecdote that describes the reason for that practice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, I had two females whose cycles synced one month behind the other; we just were not aware of it yet. We had no intent to breed them at that point and used heat diapers on the girls. We might as well have told the male to use the rhythm method of birth control for all the good those were. Between the male and the females, those pants did little more than save some cleaning wherever the girls chose to nap. So, we found the first female getting busy with our male and accepted the fact that puppies were arriving in eight to nine weeks. After their third “date,” we gave up on the chastity pants. Finally, the first females fertile period passed. The male dog was going to get some much-needed rest. Except, the second female started. We tried the good girl pants again, with the same results despite some modifications (medical tape) to try to keep the pants on this time. Two weeks into it, he was into it. At some point you realize that you have lost the upper hand and you just let nature take its course. After the second female ended her fertile period, everyone received a much-needed bath. After bath time, we left to go to the store and returned home an hour later to find the male laying on his back on the couch with all four feet straight up in the air. He did not move when we came into the house. Ever met a Yorkie that did not greet you at the door? Me either. After we put the groceries away, I went into the den and called his name several times and not a muscle twitched. OK, now I am a bit concerned. So, I go over to him to see if he is breathing. He has always had a long full coat, so it was hard to tell. So, I touched him. He was directly beneath an A/C vent, but I did not consider that at first. He was cold, and his legs were stiff. I admit, I panicked a little. I called out, saying, “Get in here! I think Glock has f*****d himself to death!” Then I picked him up and cradled him in my arms as the tears started to build in my eyes. Then I felt a pulse and realized his back was warm, but he was still asleep! He awoke over an hour later, still cradled in my arms as I was watching TV while sitting in my recliner. He looked at me and said, “I thought I was a goner: what a way to go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep animal rights groups out of their French Bulldog Puppy Mills business, each of the prefabs have heat, fans, and many have plumbing to do cleaning and to make clean water more accessible. The worst of this type of breeder cares little about cleanliness. The breeding stock rarely has interactions with humans, and from my experience, they show this by cowering away from any human that enters their area. These dogs tend towards being food aggressive because the owners feed the minimum amount of a low-quality feed. While all dogs are always hungry (just ask my pack which will wolf down a meal and then stare at you like the kids in those commercials on TV), these dogs are truly hungry, and since they are confined most of the time, they guard their food closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most Puppy Mills are AKC Certified&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French Bulldog Puppy Mills tend to advertise every litter as AKC registered, but awaiting the paperwork. Some will claim CKC status. If you are not familiar with both kennel clubs, take the time to read the differences between the two, especially considering the fact that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/advice/animal-doctor-american-kennel-club-policies-on-dog-shows-and-inspections/2016/06/23/45545824-380b-11e6-9ccd-d6005beac8b3_story.html&quot; title=&quot;Most Puppy Mills are AKC Certified&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Most Puppy Mills are AKC Certified&lt;/a&gt;. My take is that unless you are into showing dogs, who cares what paperwork they have showing lineage? The fact is, there really is no way of knowing if that litter actually came from that stud in a place that is set up to produce puppies on a regular basis. To apply for litter registration, the humans sign a statement that they witnessed the mating of the registered male with the registered female and that there was no opportunity for any other male to have scratched momma’s itch. For all you know, the puppies in one litter can have multiple baby daddies. That is not a conversation I want to have with those puppies when they are old enough to wonder about such things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backyard-french-bulldog-breeders&quot;&gt;Backyard French Bulldog Breeders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are individuals who pick a breed or two and set up a lot like a puppy mill. The only french bulldogs in the house with the humans are the ones kept as pets. The rest of the dogs are there for the purpose of breeding and making money. The operation is much smaller, and puppies become available once or twice per year. The breeding stock gets outside more than in a puppy mill, and they are much more socialized to humans. Since there are fewer animals, the owners can feed a better quality of food, and they can feed them more often. Cleanliness is a lot easier since there are only a few dogs. You can run into the same registration paperwork issues, so be skeptical about any championship lines claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pet-stores&quot;&gt;Pet Stores&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, the two breeder types above supply pet stores with puppies (and other animals). The difference is, stores have to pass health inspections, and veterinary care is required. Unfortunately, these animals are also confined to kennels most of the time. Also, unfortunately, they get handled by multiple shoppers several times each day. If you want to buy from a pet store, be cautious and observant. If the employees enforce the rule of hand washing before handling different puppies, then consider them a store that cares about the health of the puppies. If there are no signs, and the employees do not enforce a handwashing policy before and after handling each puppy, walk away without buying. Otherwise, you run the risk of buying a sick puppy. Also, understand that pet stores generally mark puppies up 50% to 100%, and sometimes more. They have rent to pay, power bills, food, insurance, employee wages, and other overhead costs. Plus, buying a puppy is an emotional decision for most people, and buyers do not consider asking if there is any wiggle room on the price of the wriggling pup because they are in a retail setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/IGCTA2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;show-breeders&quot;&gt;Show Breeders¹&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, the name says it all. These are the people who consider themselves as “professional breeders.” These breeders are heavy into showing their dogs. They research lineage and can talk about the great-great-great-grandparents of both the parents of the puppies. Their record-keeping is meticulous. They feed a very high-quality food, possibly even mixing different foods with fresh ingredients for the health benefits. They will talk your ears off about how you can get into shows and who the best trainers are. They can give you page and paragraph number on every judge and likely school you on the moods of different judges based on the color clothes they are wearing. They provide you with song and verse about their competitors, who to listen to, and who to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now comes the fun part, you will need to sign a multi-page contract with a clause that the puppy must see a vet within twenty-four to forty-eight hours; the only refund available is if the vet spots a congenital condition on the puppy during that initial visit and only after you return the puppy to them; a spay/neuter clause by a certain age with a requirement to send proof; otherwise, you pay an additional $500 fee, or more; a breed or no breed agreement; an agreement that if you decide not to keep the dog, you must return it to them at your expense; and other intrusive clauses that make you think, “Yeah, good luck enforcing that.” Since pricing is nearly as high as in pet stores, you have to wonder if they get that same type of contract when they buy a new car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;family-or-hobby-breeders--ethical-frenchies-french-bulldog-breeders&quot;&gt;Family or Hobby Breeders – Ethical Frenchie’s french bulldog breeders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is this class of breeder the sole contributor to Ethical Frenchie’s “Partner Puppies” listings. This type of breeder is just what the name implies. The dogs are bred and housed in the home. Well, the physical breeding part is done primarily by artificial insemination, Sometimes on occasion there’s an “immaculate conception” (They actually figure it out themselves despite all odds). The owners maintain routine vet visits before breeding, and once pregnant, the momma gets regular prenatal care. This type of owner obsesses over the details, such as what are the dietary needs of momma? What sort of activity restrictions does she need, and when? What do you need to do to prepare for the big day (aka very long day)? How will I know she is in labor? How will I know if she has any more puppies inside? These questions are good, and there are an endless number of them. (I will have an article about expecting mommas with pointers on the helping process in a future article.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The puppies are born inside, generally in a part of the home with very little foot traffic. The owners attend to the momma and the puppies during each birth. The humans keep meticulous records, and take pictures. Puppies get assistance finding and attaching to spigots, and momma gets help with starting the suckling reflex. The biggest puppy receives relocation assistance away from the fullest containers, and the smallest puppies get transferred to that spigot. Yes, these breeders tell Darwin to get out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A day or so after the birth, momma and pups go to the vet. The vet examines momma’s uterus areas (dogs have a two-chambered uterus, with one chamber on each side, and makes sure nothing stayed inside. Then each puppy gets a good once over from the vet. Although controversial today, this is when the  hyper vaccination process begins, which is the equivalent of injecting the puppy full of every known disease combination known to man from the chicken pocks to Ebola (just kidding, really it’s dewormer, antiparasitic stuff) for the frenchies depending on their local veterinarian and how much they want to “upsell”. A few weeks later, momma and pups make another visit to make sure all is well. The next time the puppies see the vet is for their pre-sale health report at about 8-weeks old: it is at this visit that most puppies get their second round of vaccinations at this point. If the puppies have never been outside, and momma is healthy with no worms, there is no need for deworming the puppies because there was no way for them to get worms. They received enough of momma’s immunity prior to the start of weaning off of her milk and the start of eating puppy food two weeks earlier. By the time this almost 8-week-old visit occurs, the puppies and momma should have puppy food only diets. Trust me; momma wants those needle teeth anywhere but attached to her spigots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These breeders may or may not offer registration paperwork. Likewise, they may have a puppy contract, but with significantly fewer restrictive clauses. These are the breeders who call twenty-four to forty-eight hours later to see how the puppy is doing. They may text or email after the second round of shots and stay in loose contact for a while after that. The pricing on these dogs will reflect the total cost of vet care from the start of pregnancy, all the way through to leaving for their new homes. Some people add a slight premium for males (everyone wants a male) or a particular color (Blue/Gray). As long as that premium is not ridiculous, supply and demand are likely driving any such premium. Personally, I would rather see the puppies at the same price, no matter the gender or the color, considering my business (outside of when I breed myself) is based on markup that covers our employees and their human children, balanced with  a premium-out between the other puppies in case I get stuck with one and have to start dropping the price. After about 16 to 20 weeks, most people are not willing to pay puppy-pricing for a dog without puppy breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choose-wisely--choose-ethical-frenchie-to-find-a-french-bulldog-near-you&quot;&gt;Choose Wisely – Choose Ethical Frenchie to find a french bulldog near you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter where you choose to find the new member of your family, do your breed-specific research. Every breed has different needs. Each breed has a unique set of health concerns that you need to look for while puppy-seeking. Of course, listen to the breeder, If you get a puppy from us, we connect you with the breeder upon adoption, but you should know most of what we tell you already. Ask questions about the momma and daddy, and if available, meet them. Your puppy should come with a day or two of the food they have been eating for the past couple of weeks. Ideally, we at Ethical Frenchie or the breeder themselves already told you about the brand and specific type so that you have some at home already. If you prefer a different brand, mix the food 75/25 old/new and over seven to ten days, gradually decrease the old and increase the new in the mix. This method of mixing will save you the cleanup from an upset tummy or irritated bowels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not become emotionally attached to a puppy until you have decided and placed a deposit. If there are “four other people coming later today,” let them come. If they commit to the puppy before you do, that was not the puppy for you. If there is a puppy contract, request an advanced copy via email. Read it carefully and mark areas where you have questions. Ethical Frenchie has the most thorough health guarantee, ask about it, we’re always able to modify a clause. If dealing with any other breeder/dealer, ask the breeder to add one. If that breeder declines, say goodbye. Any breeder or company whom participates in the humane production and distribution of future furbabies, that refuses or will not guarantee the health of a puppy for two to four weeks is not confident in the health of their puppies. While we provide a one year (and 2 year upon request) Keep in mind that nobody can guarantee against any health issues that are not attributable to something you did. For instance, if you feed the puppy chocolate-covered onions, and the puppy needs $2500 in vet care, we or the breeder had nothing to do with it. Or, if your puppy jumps from the couch and breaks a leg, that is all you.  With that being said, Ethical Frenchie in its time as a company serving the people in search of French bulldog babies, has some interesting stories. Just ask James or Renee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¹ Truth be told, the only reason I find show breeders slightly less ethical than family breeders is the pricing. Though, you do have to keep aware when looking at puppies from any source as some people will attempt to charge a premium price for a puppy that has flaws not acceptable in the show ring. An ethical show breeder will tell you upfront that such a puppy will not qualify to compete. If you are shopping for a family pet, so what about any markings that disqualify a puppy for show? Since you have done your homework, you know not to pay the hefty price that the breeder gets for show quality dogs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>james</name></author><category term="French Bulldog Puppy Searching" /><category term="picks" /><summary type="html">Here are the 4 types of French Bulldog Breeders near you in 2020</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/ethical_french_bulldog_puppy_sourcing.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/ethical_french_bulldog_puppy_sourcing.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">7 French Bulldog Facts that Might Surprise and Astound You</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/7-french-bulldog-facts-that-might-surprise-and-astound-you/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 French Bulldog Facts that Might Surprise and Astound You" /><published>2019-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post21</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/7-french-bulldog-facts-that-might-surprise-and-astound-you/">&lt;script src=&quot;https://apps.elfsight.com/p/platform.js&quot; defer=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;elfsight-app-812ce1aa-cd19-46bf-af79-7634f7efb5b3&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-french-bulldogs-are-a-hit-with-hollywood-royalty&quot;&gt;1. French Bulldogs are a Hit with Hollywood Royalty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With their calm French Bulldog temperament and undeniable star-quality, it may not shock you to learn that celebrities go gaga for Frenchies! In fact, Gaga, herself, has a French Bulldog named Asia Kinney who has appeared in some of the most famous photoshoots with her fashionable mom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other celebrities blessed with Frenchies include Wolverine aka Hugh Jackman, Dwyane “The Rock” Johnson, Zack Braff, Reese Wetherspoon, The Beckhams, and Martha Stewart. Leonardo DiCaprio even has a Frenchie. Do you think he knew there was a brindle Frenchie named Gamin de Pycombe aboard the Titanic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The late Carrie Fisher was also known to walk the red carpet with her French Bulldog Gary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-the-french-bulldog-could-have-been-named-the-french-english-and-american-bulldog&quot;&gt;2. The French Bulldog Could have Been Named the “French-English-and-American Bulldog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/english-bulldog-french-bulldog-puppy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Frenchie Puppy from Ethical Frenchie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The French Bulldog is a not-so-distant descendant of its larger cousin, the English Bulldog. About 150-200 years ago, while English Bulldogs seemed to get buffer and beefier, there were breeders that were developing a smaller, daintier bulldog. These more petite pooches were all the rage for English lace-makers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Industrial Revolution forced many small-business artists out of their English workshops and into the North of France. Soon, the love of these tiny bulldogs traveled from Normandy to Paris and in true Paris fashion, they became the avant-garde favorite!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The breed became more and more standardized and premiered at Westminster in 1896, even though they weren’t an AKC breed. Well, two years later Americans flipped when rose-eared Frenchies placed at Westminster. They pulled their pooches from the competition and rewrote the breed standard to dictate bat ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, all three countries played important roles in the Frenchie we know and love today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/igcta3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-frenchies-are-a-big-city-favorite&quot;&gt;3. Frenchies are a Big-City Favorite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/french-bulldog-meetup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Frenchie Puppy from Ethical Frenchie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s easy to see why Frenchies are so darn lovable, their popularity stats in the United States are remarkable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013, the French Bulldog rose to the 11th most popular breed according to the American Kennel Club. And by 2017, they climbed to the 4th spot on this prestigious list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And these big city pups have been a favorite of coastal city dwellers for years! In 2014, the Frenchie was the second most popular breed for Americans living in cities. And in 2016, they earned their place in the Big Apple as the #1 breed in New York City!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their easy-going nature and compact, but sturdy, size makes them the perfect companion to cohabitate with in an apartment. In fact, they’re one of the best roommates you can ask for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-oh-toto-theres-no-dog-like-a-frenchie&quot;&gt;4. Oh, Toto! There’s No Dog like a Frenchie!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/french-bulldog-linkedin-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Frenchie Puppy from Ethical Frenchie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the dog actor that played Toto in the film production of The Wizard of Oz, was a Cairn Terrier named Terry, the original illustrator of The Road to Oz and The Emerald City, R. A. Neill, depicted Toto as a French Bulldog. If it weren’t for a last-minute change, the film version of Toto probably would have been played by a fabulous Frenchie instead. A Wichita resident pushed for Toto to be played by a Cairn Terrier since they were the state dog of Kansas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s truly no place like home with a Frenchie waiting for you. And the Golden Brick Road would have been a bit brighter had it been graced with an adorable French Bulldog as R. A. Neill had intended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-your-frenchie-is-no-michael-phelps&quot;&gt;5. Your Frenchie is No Michael Phelps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/french-bulldog-at-the-beach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Frenchie Puppy from Ethical Frenchie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see a French Bulldog in a lake or pool, it’s probably adorned in a life jacket. This isn’t just a great fashion statement. Most Frenchies cannot swim without one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The French Bulldog’s top-heavy build makes it difficult for them to keep themselves upright and paddling. Their petite snouts also add to the complexity of Frenchie water sports. They have a tendency to sink easily and struggle to keep their button nose above the waterline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this doesn’t prevent them from being able to wade in shallow water or take a bath (even though yours may try to convince you that baths are unnecessary). This makes them perfect candidates to be spoiled with a baby pool or a flashy life vest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-ribbit-ribbit-here-comes-the-frog-dog&quot;&gt;6. Ribbit, Ribbit! Here Comes the Frog Dog!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/english-bulldog-french-bulldog-puppy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Frenchie Puppy from Ethical Frenchie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Frenchies are known for being a Yankee favorite, they rarely get called “Yankee dogs.” In fact, you’re much more likely to here one of these love bugs referred to as “frog dogs.” This may seem odd since they aren’t aquatic athletes, but it has more to do with their origin and appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, it’s seen as an antiquated nickname for people from France, but at one time “Frogs” referred to French nationals. There are many tales of how the French earned this moniker. One obvious reason it the alliteration of the “fr-,” but it is also likely that it came from the common stone pillars you’d find at the entrance of a French home, topped with a stone toad. And French Bulldogs French origin may have contributed to this lovely pet name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people are more familiar with this nickname as a reference to how our Frenchies love to lay flat on their bellies with their legs laid out behind them. While other people suggest that they earned this pseudonym because of their round faces and dark, round eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-they-may-not-swim-like-michael-phelps-but-they-skateboard-like-tony-hawk&quot;&gt;7. They May Not Swim Like Michael Phelps, But They Skateboard like Tony Hawk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have seen a Frenchie on tv skateboarding across your screen, but did you know that this breed has a knack for being skilled skateboarders?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gizmo is a French Bulldog that started to skate when he was a three-month-old pup! He even has his own YouTube Channel where you see him conquering ramps alongside human skaters. He’s totally talented, and he’s kind of Insta-famous, too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eric, or Eroc, the French bulldog is also one of the latest stars you’ll find shredding the pavement in the French Bulldog skateboarding world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether your French Bulldog is a celebrity or not, we hope you learned a little bit more about this beloved breed. Choose your favorite fact and celebrate your Frenchie’s unique heritage!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as always, if you know of anyone looking to add a new family member to their household, like, comment, share!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>renee</name></author><category term="pick" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">1. French Bulldogs are a Hit with Hollywood Royalty</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/cheap-french-bulldog-puppies-under-500_5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/cheap-french-bulldog-puppies-under-500_5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">4 Signs of a French Bulldog Scam and 4 Ways You Can Avoid Them | Ethical Frenchie</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/4-signs-of-a-french-bulldog-scam-and-4-ways-you-can-avoid-them-ethical-frenchie/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 Signs of a French Bulldog Scam and 4 Ways You Can Avoid Them | Ethical Frenchie" /><published>2019-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post22</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/4-signs-of-a-french-bulldog-scam-and-4-ways-you-can-avoid-them-ethical-frenchie/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-signs-of-a-french-bulldog-scam&quot;&gt;4 Signs of a French Bulldog Scam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/frenchbulldoggrandma2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Ethical Frenchie Customer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Con artists are quite sophisticated. They know what to ask you and how to act to appear legitimate. Make sure that you’re always cautious when shopping for a puppy and look for signs that the seller doesn’t have the best intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-they-want-you-to-commit-right-away&quot;&gt;1. They Want You to Commit Right Away&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than likely you’d never commit to buying a car or home without first seeing it. Often, they’ll be unable to Facetime or video chat so you can see the pups. What reasonable breeder would force you to pay for a puppy before being able to meet it? Often, scams will tell you the puppy in question is the last of its litter or that their phone is ringing off the hook with other people interested in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ll pressure you to place a deposit. Often, they will want you to wire them the money. While a deposit is relatively normal for a puppy, you should never send a deposit via wire or feel overly pressured to ‘hold’ a puppy. Make sure the deposit comes with a clear contract and ask if it’s refundable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scam artists are magicians when it comes to pressure. They will ask you to wire money through MoneyGram, Walmart Pay, or even PayPal to reserve your puppy. And they will give you explicit instructions to mark the payment as a gift to friends and family rather than ‘purchasing a product’ so you won’t have any refund protection. Never feel pressured to send money. In fact, if a breeder is pressuring you, this is a red flag that they’re trying to scam you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-a-deal-thats-too-good-to-be-true&quot;&gt;2. A Deal That’s Too Good to Be True&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/frenchbulldogscams.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Frenchie Puppy from Ethical Frenchie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quality purebred dogs cost money. When you see a French Bulldog listed for a remarkably low price, you should be suspicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frenchies are one of the most popular breeds in the U.S. and Europe. Puppy prices are often set by the traditional supply and demand model. So, why would someone charge one-third (or less) of the price they could get for a beautiful dog? The answer is they wouldn’t, unless there’s a scam to he had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-their-story-will-pull-at-your-heartstrings&quot;&gt;3. Their Story Will Pull at Your Heartstrings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On sites like Craigslist, and nowadays more frequently on Facebook, you’ll find that there are countless ads that will offer a purebred French Bulldog puppy as “Free to a Good Home” or “Have to Move, Can’t Bring Our Beloved Dog.” These ads often explain that they require a rehoming fee. Then, when you message them you find out that the rehoming fees are substantial or that the fees grow as you continue to message them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality is that con artists know we have hearts and would love to give a puppy in need a good home, but don’t trust these ads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-theyll-have-that-rare-color-or-size&quot;&gt;4. They’ll Have That Rare Color or Size&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/blue-frenchie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cute Blue Frenchie Puppy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Blue, Sable, and Chocolate Brindle French Bulldogs are favorites among enthusiasts, they are rare. Many opportunistic scammers will know that, too. They take advantage of hard to find colors by borrowing pictures off Google and advertising these puppies as their own. Often these puppies don’t even exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-ways-to-avoid-falling-victim-to-a-puppy-scam&quot;&gt;4 Ways to Avoid Falling Victim to a Puppy Scam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-a-picture-is-worth-1000-words&quot;&gt;1. A Picture is Worth 1,000 Words&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most Frenchie websites and ads will have a picture of a doe-eyed puppy with an adorable face, there are ways to test the photo to see if it’s legitimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to tell if a photo is legitimate is to use Google’s reverse-image search. With the website open, open another tab to Google, then drag and drop the image into the search bar and Google will scour the internet for duplicates. If there are no copies, that’s a good sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can sometimes look at the photo’s properties after downloading it to see the date it was created or if it’s a copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-take-your-time-to-research-your-breeder&quot;&gt;2. Take Your Time to Research Your Breeder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google your breeder’s email address or their business name with “reviews” added. People that get scammed want to protect others and often will report a faker to the BBB or on Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can always ask a responsible breeder for references. Reputable breeders want to be helpful and show off how happy the parents of their puppies are. Most breeders take pride in the quality of their litters and want their buyers to admire their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-meet-the-parents&quot;&gt;3. Meet the Parents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/frenchievet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Adult French Bulldogs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to remember that bringing home a new dog is a huge commitment. It’s reasonable to want to see where the puppies were raised and see their sire and dam, or at least their dam. Survey the area where the puppies are kept. Is it clean? Is it odor-free? And make sure you pay attention to the dam’s condition. Not only should she be clean, but she should be healthy and happy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-have-your-vet-check-out-the-puppy&quot;&gt;4. Have Your Vet Check out the Puppy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/vet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Frenchie at the vet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most heartbreaking outcomes of a Frenchie puppy scam is when you have the lovable fur-ball in your hands and you’re absolutely in love, just to find out that the puppy is ill or not the purebred you expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you are familiar with the French Bulldog Breed standards before you meet the puppy and its mother. Don’t be afraid to ask for papers for your puppy and its parents. And don’t exchange any money until you verify the accuracy of the papers. And you can always arrange for a DNA test prior to bringing the pup home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask your breeder if they’d accompany you to your vet to verify the puppy’s health. All too often I see warning posts on Craigslist that a dog someone brought home was ill with diseases like parvo. These scams are cruel to the dogs and the new owner. Make sure your French Bulldog is in good health before you commit to it becoming part of your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all the scams out there, finding your new French Bulldog puppy can be overwhelming, but keep in mind that nothing compares to the joy of a new dog entering your family. Avoid the risks to reap the rewards when it comes to buying a French Bulldog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re on the market for a new family member, &lt;a href=&quot;/the-ethics-of-where-to-find-a-french-bulldog-puppy-for-your-family/&quot;&gt;learn more about where our french bulldog puppies come from&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>james</name></author><category term="French Bulldog Health Issues" /><category term="news" /><category term="picks" /><summary type="html">4 Signs of a French Bulldog Scam</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/french-bulldog-scams.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/french-bulldog-scams.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why French Bulldogs Are Expensive Before Adoption</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/why-french-bulldogs-are-expensive-before-adoption/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why French Bulldogs Are Expensive Before Adoption" /><published>2019-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/post18</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/why-french-bulldogs-are-expensive-before-adoption/">&lt;p&gt;Popular among small dog breeds, Frenchies make amazing companions of human beings with their adorable appearance and pleasant personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, their high cost of adoption and raising may deter pet owners from making a purchase. Is it worth your investment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s find out &lt;strong&gt;why French bulldogs are expensive&lt;/strong&gt; in the following article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-do-french-bulldogs-cost&quot;&gt;How Much Do French Bulldogs Cost?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price of a French bulldog falls into the range of between $2000 and $6,000. It depends on locations, colors, breed lines, and some other factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dogs with a unique breeding history even cost higher, from $5,500 to $10,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can adopt a dog at a lower price of $350 to $550. The total fee often includes vaccinations and registration. You can save your money while sheltering animals in need at the same time. But since French Bulldogs are so popular, the waiting list is more than a year long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-french-bulldogs-are-expensive&quot;&gt;Why French Bulldogs Are Expensive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;they-cant-breed-naturally&quot;&gt;They can’t breed naturally&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big percentage of French Bulldogs can’t breed naturally. There are two main reasons why doing it naturally represent an issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First is their structure (big head, short back and narrow hips), the second is the fact that they are are known for having breathing difficulties and trouble with overheating. Too much “physical activity” will wear them out quickly and disable them from “getting the job done”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why breeders decide to do &lt;a href=&quot;https://wagwalking.com/treatment/artificial-insemination&quot; title=&quot;Dog Artificial Insemination&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial Insemination&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;instead&lt;/strong&gt;. There is cost involved and the price simply depends on the area. For example veterinary services are much more expensive in certain states and big cities, than in rural areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First your vet will have to monitor your females progesterone levels, to make sure you pick the most optimal time for &lt;strong&gt;Artificial insemination&lt;/strong&gt;. After that the &lt;strong&gt;Artificial insemination&lt;/strong&gt; procedure has to be done at least 3 times, to increase the chances of the breeding being successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stud-fee&quot;&gt;Stud Fee&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Stud-fee-French-Bulldogs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a  Pied French Bulldog Male Stud &quot; title=&quot;French-bulldog-stud&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have a male French Bulldog you will have to reach out to reputable breeders and pick a perfect match. The stud fee for a quality, proven French Bulldog male can be quite an investment. Anything from a 1000 – 8000$. The price varies based on pedigree, coat color, champion bloodlines, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to learn more about different&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/blog/french-bulldog-colors-explained/&quot; title=&quot;French Bulldog Colors&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;French Bulldog Colors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a specific male, that is not located in your area you sometimes have to do an “overnight semen shipping” which is a cost of its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the breeding process is costly itself, and one of the main reasons why &lt;strong&gt;French Bulldogs are expensive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;c-section&quot;&gt;C-Section&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than 80% of&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/puppies/&quot; title=&quot;French Bulldog Puppies&quot;&gt; French Bulldog Puppies&lt;/a&gt; are delivered by C-section. The over-sized heads of the puppies and narrow pelvis of the dam make natural birth a life-threatening event for the dam and the puppies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Impaired respiratory system can make the dam wear out quickly and lose the ability to push, which can result in puppies getting stuck and dying before seeing the light of day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long story short, it’s just not worth the risk, that’s why many breeders prefer to go with a costly cesarean section procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;genetic-testing-and-ofa-certification&quot;&gt;Genetic Testing and OFA Certification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/genetic testing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Genetic Testing&quot; title=&quot;Genetic-testing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before breeding your French Bulldog you have to make sure it’s 100% healthy. The last thing you want to do is breed a genetically impaired dog that will produce faulty puppies. It’s not fair to the puppies, nor their future families. The testings will cost you from 300-500$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genetic testing can be done through multiple companies like&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vgl.ucdavis.edu/&quot; title=&quot;UC Davis dog testing&quot;&gt; UC Davis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.animalgenetics.us/Home.shtml&quot; title=&quot;Animal Genetics Dog Testing&quot;&gt;Animal Genetics&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://embarkvet.com/&quot; title=&quot;Embark Vet Dog Testing&quot;&gt; Embark Vet&lt;/a&gt;, etc..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ofa.org/&quot; title=&quot;OFA&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OFA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Orthopedic Foundation for Animals will evaluate your dogs hips and detect abnormalities. If any deviations are present you should stir away from breeding that specific dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whelping-supplies&quot;&gt;Whelping Supplies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whelping a litter is like raising a baby. There are many things a breeder needs to make the mom and puppies comfortable and keep them happy and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whelping boxes, heating lamps and pads, thermometers, goat milk supplements, feeding bottles, syringes, disinfectants, pee pee pads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whelping a French Bulldog litter is on another level in many aspects. While labs could easily have their litters of pups in outdoor kennels, French bulldogs are going to need an air-conditioned housing in order to prevent heat stroke on an ordinary July day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cost of whelping supplies alone can be 500$ and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quality-dog-food&quot;&gt;Quality Dog Food&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nulo-dog-food-for-french-bulldog.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of the Nulo Salmon Puppy Dog Food&quot; title=&quot;Nulo-puppy-dog-food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that the breeder will care for the puppies for the first 8-10 weeks of their lives. THAT IS PLENTY OF FOOD. Puppies are developing and need top quality food for optimal growth. The dam needs frequent meals during pregnancy, as well as after due to nursing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of food will vary on the brand. While you can get cheaper quality dog food for 14$ per 2.5 lbs, a high end brand might cost you 3x as much. So the food expenses will be anywhere between 300$ up to 600$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that doesn’t include the multivitamins and other supplements that are beneficial to the growing puppy. Check  out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/blog/french-bulldog-care-13-best-dog-food-brands/&quot; title=&quot;Dog Food Brands&quot;&gt;dog food brands&lt;/a&gt; we recommend if you are/will soon be, in the process of whelping a French Bulldog litter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;veterinary-services&quot;&gt;Veterinary Services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French Bulldog Puppies will need a few check ups before leaving for their forever homes. In the first 8-10 weeks of their lives they will be regularly dewormed and kept up to date on shots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shots the vet administrates vary based on the area, but the most common and recommended ones are DHPP, Bordatella a.k.a Kennel Cough vaccination and Canine Influenza vaccination. Each puppies will also need to get microchipped, which costs around 45$ per puppy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned before veterinary services and cost of vaccines varies based on the area. You will pay a completely different price in New York City than you will in Missouri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vet expenses can come up to 500$ – 1000$ per one puppy. Expenses add up and contribute to the “ &lt;strong&gt;why French Bulldogs are expensive&lt;/strong&gt; “.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;french-bulldog-dams-arent-attentive-mothers&quot;&gt;French Bulldog Dams Aren’t Attentive Mothers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French Bulldog dams aren’t the most attentive mothers. In majority of breeds the dam whelps, cares, nurses and cleans the puppies with minimal human interference, but that’s not the case with French Bulldogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many cases the human will have to take over the “mother” role. Breeders will need to bottle feed the puppies, stimulate them to urinate and defecate, keep them clean, etc.. and as you can imagine that can be extremely time consuming. Especially in the first 10 days of the puppies lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first 10 days are crucial. The puppies need constant care and regular feedings (every 2 hours), which requires the breeder to be present and alert 24/7, no exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/&quot; title=&quot;French Bulldog Breeder&quot;&gt;French Bulldog Breeder&lt;/a&gt; has to keep a close watch on the litter, increasing the cost of French puppies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;miscellaneous&quot;&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do we mean by miscellaneous? Well you need to set money aside for emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it’s a puppy that needs extra care, a dam that developed complications after  whelping or a different combination of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little inconveniences here and there ad up, and at the end of the day, the breeders needs to be able to cover the expenses from raising a &lt;strong&gt;French Bulldog litter&lt;/strong&gt;. All these things are the contributors to the &lt;strong&gt;expensive price of a French Bulldog Puppy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;last-but-not-least-&quot;&gt;Last But Not Least …&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we gave you some insight and helped you understand &lt;strong&gt;why French Bulldogs are expensive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is another important factor that you have to keep in mind before getting a French Bulldog and that is - it doesn’t stop there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to maintain your Frenchies health with yearly vet check ups, expensive food and quality care. Make sure you are stable and financially ready to take on the real of being a Frenchie parent.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>james</name></author><category term="French Bulldog Health Issues" /><category term="French Bulldog Allergies" /><category term="French Bulldog Cherry Eye" /><category term="French Bulldog Health Risks" /><category term="French Bulldog Health" /><summary type="html">Popular among small dog breeds, Frenchies make amazing companions of human beings with their adorable appearance and pleasant personality.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/Why-are-French-bulldogs-expensive.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/Why-are-French-bulldogs-expensive.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cheap French Bulldog Puppies Under $500</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cheap-french-bulldog-puppies-under-500/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cheap French Bulldog Puppies Under $500" /><published>2019-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post17</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cheap-french-bulldog-puppies-under-500/">&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/IGCTA2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s something we hear too often these days. Unfortunately people don’t understand why this is impossible to find and why French Bulldogs are expensive in the first place. But please proceed on reading to get a better understanding of this complex but amazing breed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another common question is &lt;strong&gt;“How much does French Bulldog cost”&lt;/strong&gt;? Some breeders have &lt;strong&gt;inexpensive French Bulldog puppies for sale&lt;/strong&gt;. Is that good or bad? We will answer all this and more in the content below, so stay with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-cost-of-breeding-a-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;The cost of Breeding a French bulldog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/cheap-french-bulldog-puppies-under-500_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cost of Breeding a French bulldog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you decide to breed it’s important to clear your dog of any unwanted, genetic disorders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t own both a male and a female, a stud fee is required. The better quality the male (good structure, no genetic issues) the more expensive the stud fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the price can reach up to $6000, just for that. Can you imagine? Secondly due to their body shape and narrow hips, 80% of French Bulldogs can’t breed naturally and Artificial Insemination is required to produce puppies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Females then require to birth the puppies via C-section. Some of them can whelp naturally, but C-section is a preferred option if you want to make sure all the little pups survive. The procedure is not cheap, $1500-$2000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the puppies are born, they need to be fed every 2-3 hours for the first 10 days, which as you can imagine can make breeders very sleep deprived. It’s also not recommended to keep the female around babies without supervision for the first week or two. Even though &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/&quot;&gt;Frenchies&lt;/a&gt; are great moms, they can accidentally kill the babies by laying on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that come all the vet bills. Making sure all the dogs are healthy, have their shots, have been dewormed and are parasite free, etc. Don’t mention the quality food the breeders have to provide while the puppies are in their care. So if a breeder would sell &lt;strong&gt;cheap French Bulldog puppies under $500&lt;/strong&gt;, that wouldn’t cover any of the initial expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/IGCTA2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;uk-cover-container&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;uk-section uk-section-large&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;uk-container uk-container-xsmall uk-position-relative&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section-title-center uk-margin-large-bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-title uk-margin-remove uk-text-center&quot;&gt;Quick FAQ About Cheap Frenchies&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	

	&lt;ul class=&quot;uk-margin-medium-top&quot; data-uk-accordion=&quot;multiple: true&quot;&gt;
		
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a class=&quot;uk-accordion-title uk-box-shadow-hover-small uk-border-rounded&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Do $500 French Bulldog puppies exist?&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;uk-article-content uk-accordion-content link-primary&quot;&gt;Yes, French Bulldog’s exist at a shelter, but if you’re looking for a baby to raise as your own, anyone who asks $500 will likely be a scam. The prices for French Bulldog Puppies start at 2000$ on the lower end.&lt;/div&gt;                
			&lt;/li&gt;
		
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a class=&quot;uk-accordion-title uk-box-shadow-hover-small uk-border-rounded&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Why are French Bulldogs So Expensive?&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;uk-article-content uk-accordion-content link-primary&quot;&gt;French Bulldog Puppies are expensive because: 

- They cannot mate or breed naturally.
- They require artificial insemination
- French Bulldogs also cannot have natural births, each birth must be a C-Section.

However, to help you with the costs you can apply for financing for one of our puppies through our partner.
Regardless of whether you have support or not:&lt;/div&gt;                
			&lt;/li&gt;
		
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a class=&quot;uk-accordion-title uk-box-shadow-hover-small uk-border-rounded&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;I’m on a budget, can I get a French Bulldog this week?&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;uk-article-content uk-accordion-content link-primary&quot;&gt;Yes! Financing a French Bulldog Puppy is an option with Ethical Frenchie (Ethical Kennel in North Carolina). All you must do is apply with one of the 2 financing companies we work with. The process is very smooth and fast after you get approved and you can bring your Frenchie puppy home within days.
&lt;/div&gt;                
			&lt;/li&gt;
		
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a class=&quot;uk-accordion-title uk-box-shadow-hover-small uk-border-rounded&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;How Does Financing Work?&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;uk-article-content uk-accordion-content link-primary&quot;&gt;It’s quick and easy, we have had a few people apply for financing and were successful, in fact, nobody we know has been denied yet. If you are seriously interested in qualifying for a Frenchie puppy, don’t hesitate and visit us to apply today.

Check out our [Financing Options](https://ethicalfrenchie.com/french-bulldog-payment-plans/) page.&lt;/div&gt;                
			&lt;/li&gt;
		
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a class=&quot;uk-accordion-title uk-box-shadow-hover-small uk-border-rounded&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;How Long is the application process?&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;uk-article-content uk-accordion-content link-primary&quot;&gt;The process is very quick and only takes a few minutes to get pre-approved. After the paperwork is filled out by both parties, we can start scheduling the date of the puppy pick up/delivery. We work with a highly reliable flight nanny in case the delivery to another state Is required. The cost of the flight nanny (if you are out of state) can be included in your financing fee as well.&lt;/div&gt;                
			&lt;/li&gt;
		
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a class=&quot;uk-accordion-title uk-box-shadow-hover-small uk-border-rounded&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;What Are My Options Other than Financing?&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;uk-article-content uk-accordion-content link-primary&quot;&gt;You can always reach out to local rescues, or nationwide French Bulldog rescues and open your home to a French Bulldog adult in need. Another suggestion that we have would be reaching out to local breeders and inquiring about their adult French Bulldogs that they are planning to retire. The fee is usually anything between 500-1000$, depending on the breeder and the area.&lt;/div&gt;                
			&lt;/li&gt;
		
	&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/igcta3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-does-french-bulldog-cost&quot;&gt;How much does French Bulldog cost&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prices of French Bulldogs vary, but let’s say the typical price for a standard one would be around $2000. By standard we mean &lt;strong&gt;brindle, pied, fawn, cream&lt;/strong&gt;. Again it all depends on the breeding cost. Did the breeders own both male and female, did the female gave birth naturally, etc. If they invested more time and money, the price will go up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/cheap-french-bulldog-puppies-under-500_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;How much does French Bulldog cost&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will pay much more for “rare” colors and variations, such as &lt;strong&gt;blue, chocolate, black and tan or lilac French Bulldogs&lt;/strong&gt;. The price will also go up if you your dog is from a “champion blood line” or has a genetic mutation that makes him “fluffy”. The fluffy Frenchie is very rare and goes for as much as $15000 and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/cheap-french-bulldog-puppies-under-500_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blue, chocolate, black and tan or lilac French Bulldogs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/cheap-french-bulldog-puppies-under-500_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blue, chocolate, black and tan or lilac French Bulldogs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you see there are many things that affect &lt;strong&gt;how much does French Bulldog cost&lt;/strong&gt;. But if you are at the end of the day looking for a Frenchie companion because of their amusing, loving qualities, the color doesn’t play a role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/igcta3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;inexpensive-french-bulldog-puppies-for-sale&quot;&gt;Inexpensive French Bulldog Puppies For Sale&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, the part you were all waiting for. You are scrolling online with the the intention to find &lt;strong&gt;inexpensive French Bulldog puppies for sale&lt;/strong&gt; and maybe you find some. Should you be alarmed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well it really depends. There is a big chance the puppies are produced in a puppy factory with less regulation, less care, no genetic testing, didn’t receive their shots, etc. Long story short the breeder didn’t invest that much, so they can be sold for less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dogs in a puppy mill often live in dirty cages without any access to the outside world, aren’t receiving the basic care and are bred multiple times in their lifetime before dumped in a shelter. Since the females aren’t cared for, the chances are the puppies aren’t in the best shape either. So at the end of the day, you get what you paid for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time you see a post with &lt;strong&gt;inexpensive French Bulldog puppies for sale&lt;/strong&gt; at an alarming price, our advice is do as much research as possible. I know the puppy looks cute, but it might be a heartbreak waiting to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You really still want a French Bulldog but can’t swing the full amount? We offer payment plans for up-coming litters. Please reach out at any time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/igcta4.png&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can’t go beyond $500? Reach out to French Bulldog rescue groups in your state to see if they have a Frenchie in need of a loving home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/cheap-french-bulldog-puppies-under-500_5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Inexpensive French Bulldog Puppies For Sale&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>james</name></author><category term="French Bulldog Health Issues" /><category term="French Bulldog Allergies" /><category term="French Bulldog Cherry Eye" /><category term="French Bulldog Health Risks" /><category term="French Bulldog Health" /><summary type="html">It’s something we hear too often these days. Unfortunately people don’t understand why this is impossible to find and why French Bulldogs are expensive in the first place. But please proceed on reading to get a better understanding of this complex but amazing breed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/cheap-french-bulldog-puppies-under-500_hero.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/cheap-french-bulldog-puppies-under-500_hero.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>